Get ready for the human race.
Titan A.E. is a animation, science fiction,
adventure film directed by Don Bluth.
A young man finds out that he holds the key to restoring hope and ensuring survival for the human
race, while an alien species called the Drej are bent on mankind's destruction.
Cale (voice), played by Matt Damon.
Korso (voice), played by Bill Pullman.
Akima (voice), played by Drew Barrymore.
Gune (voice), played by John Leguizamo.
Preed (voice), played by Nathan Lane.
Stith (voice), played by Janeane Garofalo.
is a 2000 American animated post-apocalyptic science fiction action film directed by Don Bluth and Gary Goldman, and
starring Matt Damon, Bill Pullman, John Leguizamo, Nathan Lane, Janeane Garofalo, and Drew Barrymore.
Its title refers to the spacecraft central to the plot with A.E.
meaning "After Earth".
The animation of the film combines traditional hand-drawn created
animation with the extensive use of computer-generated imagery.
The film tells the story of a young man who receives a mission to save humanity and protect the giant ship
that can create a new planet, after the hostile alien species have destroyed the planet Earth.
Along the way, he joins up with a ship's crew and their captain, who help him race
against time and find the ship, before the aliens can destroy it.
Theatrically released on June 16, 2000, by 20th Century Fox in the United States as the third and final project produced by Fox Animation Studios,
the film received mixed reviews from critics with praise for its visuals and animation but criticism for its characters and story.
The film was also a box office failure, grossing only $36.8 million against a
budget of $75–90 million, though it has since become a cult classic.
The film explores themes of galaxy, mission, monster, dystopia, alien.
The tone is thought_provoking.